Finding Aid for John J. Loughray collection
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John J. Loughray collection 1885-2009
Loughray, John J., collector
1.1 linear feet (1 box and 1 oversize folder)
2014067 Aa 2 UAM
John J. Loughray's collection of materials relating to the history of Northern Michigan, particularly Roscommon County and logging activity.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by John J. Loughray (donor no. 11076 ) in March 2014.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The John J. Loughray collection contains photographs, postcards, printed histories, plat maps, and reminiscences relating to the history of Roscommon County, Mich., particularly Houghton Lake, Prudenville, and Roscommon as well as the logging industry. Visual materials include photographs of logging activities and locations within Northern Michigan and Loughray and his family and maps of Roscommon County. The collection also includes a documentary video, "Sawdust and Shanty Boys: Logging the Saginaw Valley White Pine," copyright 2006. The materials are arranged alphabetically by area/subject name.
Subjects:
Houghton Lake (Mich.); Logging--Michigan.; Loughray family.; Lumbering--Michigan.; Prudenville (Mich.); Resorts--Michigan--Roscommon County.; Roscommon County (Mich.)--Maps.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Lumber industry--Michigan--Roscommon County.
Genre Terms:
Booklets.; Photographs.; Postcards.; Sketch maps.; Video recordings.
- John J. Loughray collection
  - Family Photographs, 1900-1930, undated (Box 1)
  - Gerrish Township, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Grayling, circa 1939-1978, undated (Box 1)
  - The Halfway, 1988-1989, undated (Box 1)
  - Houghton Lake, circa 1924-1974, undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Logging, 1888-1939, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Logging-"Sawdust and Shanty Boys: Logging the Saginaw Valley White Pine," 2006, .mp4 file
    [Viewing access restricted to Bentley Library reading room]
  - Map and Panoramic School Photographs, 1937 undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990-2002, undated (Box 1)
  - Prudenville, 1885-2009, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Roscommon County, 1910-1998, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Roscommon Village, 1997-2007 (Box 1)
  - School Photographs/Yearbooks, circa 1938-1946 (Box 1)